CURRICULUM VITAE FOR PILISA ANITA GQOKOMA



philisaanita@gmail.com



https://github.com/Pilisa

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pilisa-gqokoma-495575169/

I am a self-driven, disciplined, and high-performance professional with excellent analytical, communication, and problem-solving skills. I enjoy being challenged and engaging with projects that require me to work outside my comfort and knowledge set. I have entry-level knowledge and experience in Software development, Networks, and Cloud Support. I would greatly appreciate an opportunity entry-level developer, networks, or a Cloud support position. I can deal with challenges and work under pressure whilst maintaining a customer-centric ethic.

PERSONAL DETAILS

· Name and Surname: Pilisa Gqokoma · Date of birth: 24 - August - 1995

· Gender: Female

· Residence & Nationality: Cape Town, South Africa · Language: IsiXhosa (Home language)

English (read, write, and speak fluently)

EDUCATION

POSTGRADUATE DIPLOMA | CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (CPUT) | JAN 2022 - DEC 2023

· Course: Information and Communication Technology - Applications Development

Postgraduate Diploma Qualification:

ADVANCED DIPLOMA | CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (CPUT) | JAN - DEC 2021

· Course: Information and Communication Technology - Applications Development

· Qualification: Advanced Diploma

DIPLOMA | CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (CPUT) | JAN. 2017 - DEC. 2020

Information and Communication Technology - Applications Development · Course:

· Qualification: National Diploma

HIGHER CERTIFICATE | CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (CPUT) | JAN. 2015 - DEC. 2016

· Course: **Information and Communication Technology**

Higher Certificate · Qualification:

NATIONAL SENIOR CERTIFICATE (NSC) | CENTRE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY | 2013

· High school: KwaZakhele High School

· Certification: National Senior Certificate (NSC)

CERTIFICATES/ COURSES

- · Microsoft
- · SAP S/4HANA

- · Responsive Web design
- · Structured Query Language (SQL) Using SAS
- · Cisco Academy

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE AREAS

Azure Git React SpringBoot **SDLC** 4.5 JavaScript HTML & CSS 3,8 Docker 1.5 SQL 2,5 Testing Scrum Agile Methodology

Scale from 1 -5 (least to most experienced)

EXPERIENCE

CLOUD SUPPORT OFFICER AND FRONT-END DEVELOPER EMPLOYEE AT ADDPAY – STELLENBOSCH TECHNOPARK | 16 SEPTEMBER 2022 – CURRENT

I am currently working as a cloud Support Officer and Junior Front-End Developer at Add Pay (A Fin Tech Company).

As A Cloud Support Officer, I provide:

- Remote/ cloud support to Merchants by identifying and resolving hardware or software problems.
- Perform routine server maintenance tasks, such as monitoring performance, checking logs, updating software, installing patches, etc.
- Technical support by responding to inbound calls or emails from customers or users who have technical issues with their systems.
- Monitoring servers and applications for signs of problems or unexpected activity
- Determine the cause of a problem and suggest solutions based on experience with similar issues.
- Provide technical support by creating documentation and training materials for new computer system users.

As a FRONT-END DEVELOPER I:

- · Build interactive, professional-looking websites and systems.
- · Make web page designs adapt to different screen sizes using a responsive grid layout.
- · Add navigation and other design elements, to separatedata and
- · Display using JavaScript objects.
- · Test the functionality of the systems.

Below are some Technologies/Systems I am working with

- · Genesis (Cloud System)
- Fresh Desk (Cloud System)
- · Paycloud (Cloud System)
- · API (Cloud System)
- · Java
- · JavaScript
- · Software Testing
- · HTML and CSS
- · React

IT INTERN || WESTERN CAPE EDUCATIONAL DEPARTMENT AT WCED (CTLI) || 15 MAR. 2021 - 16 SEPTEMBER 2022

After completing my Diploma, I received employment from the Western Cape Educational Department (WCED) as an Intern. Some of my key tasks are to maintain and improve the website, work as part of the application design and development, work with Learning Management Systems like Moodle, I also run tests (manual and automated) to verify the functionality of the software, I also provide technical support. Below are some of the technologies I have had the pleasure of being exposed to:

- · Java
- JavaScript
- · Software Testing
- · HTML and CSS
- · React
- Bootstrap

REFERENCES

- 1. Mr. Christo Davids
- Manager at WCED (CTLI)
- · +27 (0) 79 542 1926
- 2. Miss. Qaphela Tyala
- · Support Officer Addpay
- · 0678648316

- 3. Reverend Professor Simon
- · Church Leader
- · +27(0)84 480 0910